The battle for the lawn is on.
The Ant Bully is a fantasy, adventure, animation film directed by John A. Davis.
Fed up with being targeted by the neighborhood bully, 10-year-old Lucas Nickle
vents his frustrations on the anthill in his front yard ...
until the insects shrink him to the size of a bug with a magic elixir.
Convicted of "crimes against the colony," Lucas can only regain his
freedom by living with the ants and learning their ways.
Lucas Nickle (voice), played by Zach Tyler Eisen.
Hova (voice), played by Julia Roberts.
Queen (voice), played by Meryl Streep.
Zoc (voice), played by Nicolas Cage.
Stan Beals (voice), played by Paul Giamatti.
Fugax (voice), played by Bruce Campbell.
The Ant Bully is a 2006 American animated fantasy comedy film
written, directed, and co-produced by John A.
Loosely based on the 1999 children's book of the same name, it tells the story of Lucas Nickle, a young
boy who, after terrorizing a colony of ants, is shrunken and ordered to work amongst them.
The film was produced by Legendary Pictures, Playtone, and DNA Productions, and features the voice talents of Julia
Roberts, Nicolas Cage, Meryl Streep, Paul Giamatti, Regina King, Bruce Campbell, and Zach Tyler Eisen.
Released on July 28, 2006, by Warner Bros.
Pictures, The Ant Bully received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $55 million
against a $50 million budget, making it a box-office disappointment.
This led to extensive layoffs at DNA Productions
and, ultimately, the studio's closure.
The Ant Bully was Ricardo Montalbán's final film role before his death in 2009.
The film explores themes of ant-hill, ant, child hero, shrinking, bully.
The tone is lighthearted.